<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Motivational Stories</title>
        <link>http://www.abhishekraj007.github.io</link>
        <description>Collection of motivational stories</description>
        <item>
            <title>The important things in life</title>
            <link>#</link>
            <guid></guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2016</pubDate>
            <description>

                <![CDATA[
                    <p>A philosophy professor stood before his class with some items on the table in front of him. When the class began, wordlessly he picked up a very large and empty mayonnaise jar and proceeded to fill it with rocks, about 2 inches in diameter.</p>
                    <p>He then asked the students if the jar was full. They agreed that it was.</p>
                    <p>So the professor then picked up a box of pebbles and poured them into the jar. He shook the jar lightly. The pebbles, of course, rolled into the open areas between the rocks.</p>
                    <p>He then asked the students again if the jar was full. They agreed it was.</p>
                    <p>The professor picked up a box of sand and poured it into the jar. Of course, the sand filled up the remaining open areas of the jar.</p>
                    <p>He then asked once more if the jar was full. The students responded with a unanimous &ldquo;Yes.&rdquo;</p>
                    <p>&ldquo;Now,&rdquo; said the professor, &ldquo;I want you to recognize that this jar represents your life. The rocks are the important things &ndash; your family, your partner, your health, your children &ndash; things that if everything else was lost and only they remained, your life would still be full. The pebbles are the other things that matter &ndash; like your job, your house, your car. The sand is everything else, the small stuff.&rdquo;</p>
                    <p>&ldquo;If you put the sand into the jar first,&rdquo; he continued, &ldquo;there is no room for the pebbles or the rocks. The same goes for your life. If you spend all your time and energy on the small stuff, you will never have room for the things that are important to you. Pay attention to the things that are critical to your happiness. Play with your children. Take your partner out dancing. There will always be time to go to work, clean the house, give a dinner party, or fix the disposal.&rdquo;</p>
                    <p>&ldquo;Take care of the rocks first &ndash; the things that really matter. Set your priorities. The rest is just sand.&rdquo;</p>
                    ]]>

            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Live and Work</title>
            <link>#</link>
            <guid></guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2016</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                    <p>Father was a hardworking man who delivered bread as a living to support his wife and three children. He spent all his evenings after work attending classes, hoping to improve himself so that he could one day find a better paying job. Except for Sundays, Father hardly ate a meal together with his family. He worked and studied very hard because he wanted to provide his family with the best money could buy.</p>
                <p>Whenever the family complained that he was not spending enough time with them, he reasoned that he was doing all this for them. But he often yearned to spend more time with his family.</p>
                <p>The day came when the examination results were announced. To his joy, Father passed, and with distinctions too! Soon after, he was offered a good job as a senior supervisor which paid handsomely.</p>
                <p>Like a dream come true, Father could now afford to provide his family with life&rsquo;s little luxuries like nice clothing, fine food and vacation abroad.</p>
                <p>However, the family still did not get to see father for most of the week. He continued to work very hard, hoping to be promoted to the position of manager. In fact, to make himself a worthily candidate for the promotion, he enrolled for another course in the open university.</p>
                <p>Again, whenever the family complained that he was not spending enough time with them, he reasoned that he was doing all this for them. But he often yearned to spend more time with his family.</p>
                <p>Father&rsquo;s hard work paid off and he was promoted. Jubilantly, he decided to hire a maid to relieve his wife from her domestic tasks. He also felt that their three-room flat was no longer big enough, it would be nice for his family to be able to enjoy the facilities and comfort of a condominium. Having experienced the rewards of his hard work many times before, Father resolved to further his studies and work at being promoted again. The family still did not get to see much of him. In fact, sometimes Father had to work on Sundays entertaining clients. Again, whenever the family complained that he was not spending enough time with them, he reasoned that he was doing all this for them. But he often yearned to spend more time with his family.</p>
                <p>As expected, Father&rsquo;s hard work paid off again and he bought a beautiful condominium overlooking the coast of Singapore. On the first Sunday evening at their new home, Father declared to his family that he decided not to take anymore courses or pursue any more promotions. From then on he was going to devote more time to his family.</p>
                <p>Father did not wake up the next day.</p>
                
                ]]>
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Give time to our family</title>
            <link>#</link>
            <guid></guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2016</pubDate>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                <p>After 21 years of marriage, my wife wanted me to take another woman out to dinner and a movie. She said, &ldquo;I love you, but I know this other woman loves you and would love to spend some time with you.&rdquo;</p>
            <p>The other woman that my wife wanted me to visit was my MOTHER, who has been a widow for 19 years, but the demands of my work and my three children had made it possible to visit her only occasionally. That night I called to invite her to go out for dinner and a movie. &ldquo;What&rsquo;s wrong, are you well?&rdquo; she asked.</p>
            <p>My mother is the type of woman who suspects that a late night call or a surprise invitation is a sign of bad news. &ldquo;I thought that it would be pleasant to spend some time with you,&rdquo; I responded. &ldquo;Just the two of us.&rdquo; She thought about it for a moment, and then said, &ldquo;I would like that very much.&rdquo;</p>
            <p>That Friday after work, as I drove over to pick her up I was a bit nervous. When I arrived at her house, I noticed that she, too, seemed to be nervous about our date. She waited in the door with her coat on. She had curled her hair and was wearing the dress that she had worn to celebrate her last wedding anniversary. She smiled from a face that was as radiant as an angel&rsquo;s. &ldquo;I told my friends that I was going to go out with my son, and they were impressed, &ldquo;she said, as she got into the car. &ldquo;They can&rsquo;t wait to hear about our meeting.&rdquo;</p>
            <p>We went to a restaurant that, although not elegant, was very nice and cozy. My mother took my arm as if she were the First Lady. After we sat down, I had to read the menu. Her eyes could only read large print. Half way through the entries, I lifted my eyes and saw Mom sitting there staring at me. A nostalgic smile was on her lips. &ldquo;It was I who used to have to read the menu when you were small,&rdquo; she said. &ldquo;Then it&rsquo;s time that you relax and let me return the favor,&rdquo; I responded. During the dinner, we had an agreeable conversation &ndash; nothing extraordinary but catching up on recent events of each other&rsquo;s life. We talked so much that we missed the movie. As we arrived at her house later, she said, &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll go out with you again, but only if you let me invite you.&rdquo; I agreed.</p>
            <p>&ldquo;How was your dinner date?&rdquo; asked my wife when I got home. &ldquo;Very nice. Much more so than I could have imagined,&rdquo; I answered.</p>
            <p>A few days later, my mother died of a massive heart attack. It happened so suddenly that I didn&rsquo;t have a chance to do anything for her. Some time later, I received an envelope with a copy of a restaurant receipt from the same place mother and I had dined. An attached note said: &ldquo;I paid this bill in advance. I wasn&rsquo;t sure that I could be there; but nevertheless, I paid for two plates &ndash; one for you and the other for your wife. You will never know what that night meant for me. I love you, son.&rdquo;</p>
            <p>At that moment, I understood the importance of saying in time: &ldquo;I LOVE YOU&rdquo; and to give our loved ones the time that they deserve. Nothing in life is more important than your family. Give them the time they deserve, because these things cannot be put off till &ldquo;some other time.&rdquo;</p>
            
            ]]>

            </description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
